Please. Please.
Pitié...
I have credits. Take them.
J'ai des crédits, prenez-les.
He says you spilled his drink.
Il dit que tu as renversé son verre.
It's fine.
C'est rien.
It's on me.
C'est ma tournée.
Here.
Tiens.
Thank you! Thank you very much!
Merci infiniment.
You have my heartfelt gratitude.
Vous avez toute ma gratitude.
You know what? Here.
Au fait... tenez.
You take my credits.
Prenez mes crédits.
Buy yourself a drink.
Offrez-vous un verre.
Is that a bounty puck?
Un palet de traque ?
Is that me?
C'est moi ?
Look... Uh, there must be some mistake.
Attendez.
I can get you more credits.
J'aurai d'autres crédits.
I can bring you in warm...
Je peux te garder au chaud
Or I can bring you in cold.
ou te refroidir.
I need passage to the yards.
Je dois rejoindre les docks.
No droids.
Pas de droïde.
Where to?
Où on va ?
You know what he's looking for?
Vous savez ce qu'il cherche ?
You're looking for Ravinaks, right?
Des Ravinaks, hein ?
It's clear right now.
Rien pour l'instant !
But be careful near the port.
Mais attention, près du port.
Everyone dumps their Gray Holds out.
Tout le monde y jette ses vieilles carcasses.
They think the whole entire planet is their own personal stink pit.
Ils prennent toute la planète pour une décharge publique.
Here you are.
On y est.
- You're kidding me, right? - Get out.
- C'est une blague ? - Descends.
I'll hire us a Livery Cruiser.
Je vais louer un croiseur.
No big deal. It won't come out of your end.
Ça ne vous coûtera rien.
I'll pay for it.
C'est moi qui paie.
I'm just trying to make it pleasant.
Ce sera plus confortable.
Hey, it's time to go, so let's settle up.
Il est temps. Réglez la course.
I'd stay off the ice if I were you.
J'éviterais la glace, à votre place.
You think there's really something to worry about?
Vous croyez qu'il faut s'inquiéter ?
Open the hatch! Open the hatch!
Ouvrez l'écoutille !
Dank farrik, that was close!
Dank farrik, on a eu chaud !
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
Bon sang...
"Stay off the ice."
"Éviter la glace". L'euphémisme du millénaire !
It's taking us down. What're you doing?
Il nous entraîne ! Que faites-vous ?
It's got us. It's gonna take us under.
Il va nous faire couler.
Where you going?
Où allez-vous ?
You got to do something! We got to get out of here!
Faites quelque chose, décollez !
Let's go. Let's go. Let's go.
Vite, vite, vite, vite...
I like your ship. She's a classic.
J'adore votre vaisseau.
Razor Crest, am I right?
Un Razor Crest, hein ?
Pre-Empire?
Pré-Empire ?
I have a lot of credits, by the way.
J'ai des tas de crédits.
That's why I offered to hail a Cruiser.
Je voulais louer un croiseur.
How much are they paying you?
Ils vous paient combien ?
Is it true that you guys never take off your helmets?
C'est vrai que vous n'enlevez jamais votre casque ?
I think I have to use the vacc tube.
J'ai besoin de l'évac-tube.
I mean I can do it here,
Je peux le faire ici, mais
but if you've never seen a Fledgling Mythrol evacuate their thorax,
si vous n'avez jamais vu un Mythrol évacuer son thorax,
you're a lucky guy, trust me.
vous avez de la chance.
Clearly, there's nowhere for me to go.
Je ne peux pas aller loin.
So, uh...
Alors,
I'm gonna look for that vacc tube if it's all the same to you?
je vais chercher cet évac-tube, d'accord ?
Great.
Super.
Found it!
Je l'ai trouvé !
Thanks. It might take a while.
Merci. J'en ai pour un moment.
I'm molting.
Je vais muer.
Oh, this feels a lot better.
Je me sens mieux.
I haven't evacuated since the solstice.
Je n'ai pas évacué depuis le solstice.
I was hoping to be free for Life Day.
J'espérais assister à la Fête de la Vie.
Maybe even, uh...
Peut-être même
Get home to the family.
rentrer voir ma... famille.
But I guess that's not gonna happen this year.
Mais ce n'est pas pour cette année.
Probably not.
Sans doute pas.
Ah, that was fast.
Tu as fait vite.
Did you catch them all?
Tu les as tous capturés ?
Good. I'll begin the off-load.
On va décharger.
These are Imperial Credits.
Des crédits impériaux ?
They still spend.
Ils ont encore cours.
I don't know if you heard, but the Empire is gone.
Je te rappelle que l'Empire a disparu.
It's all I've got.
Je n'ai que ça.
Save the theatrics.
Arrête ton cirque.
Fine, I'll...
Bien.
I can do Calamari Flan...
J'ai aussi des Flans Calamari.
But I can only pay half.
Mais je paierai la moitié.
Fine.
Bien.
Hmm. I have a bail jumper...
Violation de conditionnelle.
A bail jumper,
Une autre.
another bail jumper, a wanted smuggler.
Encore une. Un trafiquant.
I'll take them all.
Je les prends tous.
No. Hold on.
Une seconde.
There are other members of the Guild, and this is all I have.
Il y a d'autres membres de la Guilde, et je n'ai que ça.
Why so slow?
Pourquoi si peu ?
It's not slow at all, actually. Very busy.
En fait, on croule sous la demande.
They just don't want to pay Guild rates.
Mais ils refusent les tarifs de la Guilde.
They don't mind if things get sloppy.
Ils se fichent que ça tourne mal.
- What's your highest bounty? - Not much.
- Ta plus grosse prime ? - Pas terrible.
Five thousand.
5 000.
That won't even cover fuel these days.
Ça couvre à peine le carburant.
There is one job.
Il y a bien un job...
Let's see the puck.
Fais voir le palet.
No puck.
Pas de palet.
Face to face.
Un face à face.
Direct commission.
Commission en direct.
Deep pocket.
Il a les moyens.
Underworld?
La pègre ?
All I know is no chain code.
En tout cas, pas de code d'identité.
Do you want the chit or not?
Tu en veux, ou pas ?
What else did he say?
Et quoi d'autre ?
He said you were the best in the parsec.
Que vous étiez le meilleur du parsec.
- Freeze! - No!
- Pas un geste ! - Lâchez vos armes !
No, no, no, no. Pardon. Uh, sorry.
Pardon, désolé.
I didn't mean to alarm.
Je ne voulais pas vous alarmer.
This is Doctor Pershing.
Voici le Dr Pershing.
Please excuse his lack of decorum.
Excusez son manque de décorum.
His enthusiasm outweighs his discretion.
Son enthousiasme l'emporte sur sa discrétion.
Please lower your blaster.
Baissez votre blaster.
Have them lower theirs first.
Eux d'abord.
We have you four to one.
On est à quatre contre un.
I like those odds.
Je prends les paris.
He also said you were expensive.
Il a dit aussi que vous étiez cher.
Very expensive.
Très cher.
Please sit.
Veuillez vous asseoir.
Beskar?
Du Beskar ?
Go ahead. It's real.
Allez-y. Il est authentique.
This is only a down payment.
Ce n'est qu'une avance.
I have a camtono of Beskar waiting for you upon delivery of the asset.
Un camtono de Beskar vous attend à la livraison de l'objectif.
Alive.
Vivant.
Yes. Alive.
Oui. Vivant.
Although, I acknowledge
Cela dit, je sais
that bounty hunting is a complicated profession.
que Chasseur de Primes est une profession difficile.
This being the case,
Le cas échéant,
proof of termination is also acceptable for a lower fee.
une preuve d'exécution sera acceptable, avec un rabais.
That is not what we agreed upon.
Ce n'est pas ce qui a été convenu.
I'm simply being pragmatic.
Je suis seulement pragmatique.
Let's see the puck.
Voyons le palet.
I'm afraid discretion dictates
La discrétion nécessite
a less traditional agreement.
un arrangement moins conventionnel.
We can only offer you a tracking fob.
Vous n'aurez qu'un capteur de positionnement.
What's the chain code?
Et le code d'identité ?
We can only provide the last four digits.
Seulement les quatre derniers chiffres.
Their age? That's all you can give me?
Son âge ? C'est tout ?
Yes. They're 50 years old.
Oui. Il a 50 ans.
We can also give you last reported positional data.
Vous aurez aussi sa dernière localisation.
Between that and the fob,
Entre ça et le capteur,
a man of your skill should make short work of this.
un homme de votre talent devrait s'en sortir vite.
The Beskar belongs back into the hands of a Mandalorian.
Le Beskar doit revenir à un Mandalorien.
It is good to restore the natural order of things
Il est bon de restaurer l'ordre des choses,
after a period of such disarray,
après autant d'anarchie.
don't you agree?
N'est-ce pas ?
This was gathered in the Great Purge.
Ça provient de la Grande Purge.
It is good it is back with the Tribe.
Sa place est dans la Tribu.
A pauldron would be in order.
Un pauldron s'impose.
- Has your signet been revealed? - Not yet.
- On t'a révélé ton blason ? - Pas encore.
Soon.
Ça viendra.
This is extremely generous. The excess will sponsor many Foundlings.
C'est très généreux. L'excédent aidera bien des Orphelins.
That's good.
Tant mieux.
I was once a Foundling.
J'en étais un moi-même.
I know.
Je sais.
You are a bounty hunter.
Tu es chasseur de primes.
I will help you.
Je vais t'aider.
I have spoken.
Ainsi ai-je parlé.
Many have passed through.
Beaucoup sont venus.
They seek the same one as you.
Avec le même objectif que toi.
Did you help them?
Tu les as aidés ?
They died.
Ils sont morts.
Well, then I don't know if I want your help.
Je ne suis pas sûr de vouloir ton aide.
You do.
Tu te trompes.
I can show you to the encampment.
Je peux te conduire au campement.
What's your cut?
Tu prends combien ?
Half.
La moitié.
Half the bounty to guide? Seems steep.
La moitié de la prime ? C'est cher payé.
No. Half of the blurrg you helped capture.
La moitié des blurrgs que tu m'as aidé à capturer.
The blurrg? You can keep them both.
Les blurrgs ? Tu peux les garder.
No, you will need one.
Non, il t'en faudra un.
To ride.
Comme monture.
The way is impossible to pass without a blurrg mount.
Le chemin est impraticable sans un blurrg.
I don't know how to ride blurrg.
Je ne sais pas monter un blurrg.
I have spoken.
Ainsi ai-je parlé.
Perhaps if you removed your helmet.
Et si tu enlevais ton casque ?
Perhaps he remembers I tried to roast him.
Il doit se souvenir que je voulais le rôtir.
This is a female. The males are all eaten during mating.
C'est une femelle. Les mâles se font dévorer pendant l'accouplement.
I don't have time for this.
Pas le temps.
Do you have a Landspeeder or Speeder bike that I could hire?
Tu as un landspeeder ou un speederbike à louer ?
You are Mandalorian!
Tu es un Mandalorien !
Your ancestors rode the great Mythosaur.
Tes ancêtres chevauchaient le Mythosaure.
Surely you can ride this young foal.
Tu peux dompter cette jeune furie.
Easy. Easy.
Doucement.
Now, all right. Settle down.
C'est bien. Du calme.
Settle. Settle.
Gentille.
That's good. That's good.
C'est bien.
Easy. Okay.
Doucement.
That is where you'll find your quarry.
C'est là que tu trouveras ta proie.
Please. You deserve this.
Tiens. Tu le mérites.
Since these ones arrived,
Depuis leur arrivée,
this territory has been an endless stream
ce territoire a vu déferler
of mercenaries seeking reward and bringing destruction.
des mercenaires assoiffés d'argent et de destruction.
Then why did you guide me?
Pourquoi m'avoir guidé ?
They do not belong here.
Leur place n'est pas ici.
Those that live here come to seek peace.
Ceux qui vivent ici recherchent la paix.
There will be no peace until they're gone.
Il n'y en aura pas tant qu'ils seront là.
Then why do you help?
Pourquoi m'avoir aidé ?
I have never met a Mandalorian.
Je n'avais jamais vu de Mandalorien.
I've only read the stories.
Seulement lu leurs exploits.
If they are true, you will make quick work of it.
S'ils sont vrais, tu feras vite.
Then there will again be peace.
Et la paix reviendra.
I have spoken.
Ainsi ai-je parlé.
Bounty Droid.
Un droïde chasseur de primes.
Subparagraph 16 of the Bondsman Guild protocol waiver
L'alinéa 16 de la dérogation au protocole de la Guilde
compels you to immediately produce said asset.
vous impose de livrer l'objectif.
Droids.
Les droïdes...
Subparagraph 16 of the Bondsman Guild protocol waiver
L'alinéa 16 de la dérogation au protocole de la Guilde
compels you to immediately produce said asset.
vous impose de livrer l'objectif.
IG Unit! Stand down.
Unité IG ! Dépose les armes !
I'm in the Guild!
Je fais partie de la Guilde !
You are a Guild member?
Toi, de la Guilde ?
I thought I was the only one on assignment.
Je croyais être seul sur cette mission.
That makes two of us.
Eh bien on est deux.
So much for the element of surprise.
Adieu l'élément de surprise.
Sadly, I must ask for your fob.
Il me faut ton capteur.
I have already issued the writ of seizure. The bounty is mine.
J'ai publié l'avis de saisie. La prime me revient.
Unless I'm mistaken, you are, as of yet, empty-handed.
Sauf erreur, tu as encore les mains vides.
This is true.
C'est exact.
- I have a suggestion. - Proceed.
- J'ai une suggestion. - J'écoute.
We split the reward.
On partage la prime.
This is acceptable.
Acceptable.
Great. Now let's regroup, out of harm's way, and form a plan.
Parfait. Rejoins-moi à l'abri, et élaborons un plan.
I will of course receive the reputation merits
Mais je recevrai les honneurs
associated with the mission.
associés à la mission.
Can we talk about this later?
On peut en parler plus tard ?
I require an answer if I am to proceed...
J'exige une réponse pour pouvoir...
Oh, no. Alert. Alert. Alert.
Alerte... alerte...
He's in there!
Il est là-dedans !
Affirmative.
Affirmatif.
Up top!
Le toit !
It appears we are trapped.
Nous sommes piégés.
I will initiate self-destruct sequencing.
J'enclenche l'autodestruction.
Whoa, you're what?
Quoi ?
Manufacturers Protocol dictates I cannot be captured.
Mon protocole m'interdit d'être capturé.
- I must self-destruct. - Do not self-destruct.
- Je dois m'autodétruire. - Pas question.
Cover me!
Couvre-moi !
Go! Go! Go! There's too many!
Cours ! Il y en a trop !
They got us pinned.
Ils nous ont coincés.
I will initiate self-destruct.
Je vais m'autodétruire.
Do not self-destruct! We're shooting our way out.
Ne t'autodétruis pas ! On peut s'en sortir.
New plan!
Nouveau plan !
Beginning self-destruct countdown.
- Compte à rebours autodestruction. - Arrête !
Draw their fire, I'll take it out.
Attire-les, je les neutraliserai.
- Acceptable. - Go!
Acceptable.
Well done.
Bien joué.
I will disengage self-destruct initiative.
Je désactive l'autodestruction.
You know, you're not so bad.
Tu n'es pas si mal.
- For a droid. - Agreed.
- Pour un droïde. - Je confirme.
That blaster hit looks nasty. You okay?
Ce blaster t'a amoché. Ça va ?
Running a quick diagnostic.
Diagnostic rapide.
It has missed my central wiring harness.
Il a raté mon harnais central.
Is that good?
Et c'est bien ?
Well, now we just need to get the door open.
On n'a plus qu'à ouvrir cette porte.
Anyone else?
Quelqu'un d'autre ?
The tracking fob is still active.
Le capteur est toujours actif.
My sensors indicate that there is a life form present.
Les miens indiquent la présence d'une forme de vie.
Wait.
Attends.
They said 50 years old.
Ils avaient dit 50 ans.
Species age differently.
L'âge dépend des espèces.
Perhaps it could live many centuries.
Peut-être qu'il vit des siècles.
Sadly, we'll never know.
Nous ne le saurons hélas jamais.
We'll bring it in alive.
Nous le ramènerons en vie.
The commission was quite specific. The asset was to be terminated.
La mission consistait à anéantir l'objectif.